妈妈,能不能就那么一次,我们一起吃饭时
Mother,just once,can we go to lunch...
你不要谈论我的衣着和我的工作
...and not talk about what I'm wearing or where my career is going?
包括我和谁约会
Or who I'm dating.
-准备好买单了? -天哪,是的
-Ready for the check? -God,yes.
-我来吧. -不,亲爱的
-I'll take it. -No,darling.
我说了我来.这里,拿着,走,跑
I said I'll take it. Here,take it. Go. Run.
你真贴心
Very sweet.
-他们到底为什么给你工钱. -因为工作
-And on what they pay you -Career.
你不用担心我.我做的很好
You don't have to worry about me. I'm doing fine.
我想这张卡被禁用了
I'm afraid this has been denied.
这不可能
That's impossible.
好吧,亲爱的,用这张吧
That's all right,dear. Here you go.
六人行 第1季 第21集 假莫妮卡
The One With The Fake Monica
怎么会有人知道你的信用卡号码?
How'd someone get your card number?
我也不知道,你看他们花了多少钱
No idea. Look how much they spent.
你只须付你所买的东西
You only have to pay for the stuff you bought.
我知道,他真是挥霍无度
Still,it's just such reckless spending.
我想他偷去你的信用卡时
When somebody steals...
根本就已忘了王法
...they've already thrown caution to the wind.
真是个变态,花了69.95元买“神奇拖把”
Wow,what a geek. They spent $69. 95 on a Wonder Mop.
我买的
That's me.
你看,我说变态,我的意思是
You see,when I say geek,I mean
怎么回事,你花了70块买一把拖把,你是个变态
The hell with it,you bought a $70 mop,you're a geek.
哦,讨厌.罗斯,他又这么干了
Oh,yuck. Ross,he's doing it again.
马修,别再侵犯那盏灯了
Marcel,stop humping the lamp.
停止侵犯.现在,马修,过来,马修
Stop humping. Now,Marcel,come Come here,Marcel.
不,又到我房里了,我去抓他出来
Oh,no. Not in my room. I'll get him.
罗斯,你得想办法阻止
You've got to do something about that.
什么?这只是个阶段
What? It's just a phase.
我们当时也是这么说乔伊的
Well,that's what we said about Joey.
你们能多给点理解吗?
You'd think you would be more understanding.
我明白.可是我们不能
I know. But we're not.
你们冷静点行吗?这又没什么了不起
Would you all relax? It's not that big a deal.
-马修,停,坏猴子 -又怎么了?
-Marcel,stop it. Marcel. Bad monkey. -What?
我只能说,我的好奇乔治（猴子模样的玩具）不再好奇了
Let's say my Curious George is no longer curious.
莫妮卡,你还是无法释怀
You are not still going over that thing.
-这女人过着我的生活 -什么?
-This woman's living my life. -What?
她过着我的生活,而且过得比我好
She's living my life,and she's doing it better than me.
看,她买的戏票是我一直想看的戏
Look at this. Look. She buys tickets to plays I wanna see.
她买的衣服是我早就想买的
She shops where I'm afraid of the salespeople.
-她花了三百块买艺术用品 -你又不是艺术家
-She spent $300 on art supplies. -You're not an artist.
如果有艺术用品,我或许已是个艺术家
I might be if I had the supplies.
我本来可以的,只是现在不是
I mean,I could do all this stuff. Only I don't.
莫妮卡,别泄气,你做的工作很酷
Oh,Monica,come on. You do cool things.
真的?我们来做比较,好吗?
Really? Let's compare,shall we?
现在说“好吗”时间有点太晚了
Oh,it's so late for "shall we."
我到过公园骑马吗?
Do I horseback ride in the park?
-我在新学校上过课吗? -没有
-Do I take classes at the New School? -No.
她拥有我想要的一切,而且她没有我妈
She's got everything I want,and she doesn't have my mother.
-乔伊帕波尼如何? -不好,太有种族意味了
-How about Joey Paponi? -No,still too ethnic.
-我的经纪人认为,我该取个中立一点的名字 -乔伊瑞士?
-My agent wants a more neutral name. -Joey Switzerland?
而且,我应该就是乔,乔伊让我感觉…这么大
Plus,I think it should be Joe. Joey makes me sound like I'm this big:
可我不是
Which I'm not.
乔…乔斯大林?
Joe,Joe,Joe Stalin?
斯大林
Stalin.
我认识这名字吗?听得很熟悉
Do I know that name? It sounds familiar.
我没印象
Well,it does not ring a bell with me.
但是你是深深陷在表演事业之中了啊
But you're more plugged into that show business thing.
乔斯大林
Joe Stalin.
这名字很好
You know,that's pretty good.
或许你想试试乔瑟夫
You might wanna try Joseph.
乔瑟夫斯大林（前苏联领导人）
Joseph Stalin.
-我好像记得这个名字 -是的
-I think you'd remember that. -Yes.
《再见，小鸟》（著名电影）乔瑟夫斯大林主演
Bye Bye Birdie,starring Joseph Stalin.
《屋顶上的提琴手》（著名电影）中的乔瑟夫斯大林
Joseph Stalin is the Fiddler on the Roof.
对,我是莫妮卡盖勒
Hi. Yes,this is Monica Geller.
我想有在你们那里上课,我想知道是哪些课
I'm taking some classes with you,and I was wondering what they were.
我最近头部受伤,只记得一些数字了
I've had a recent head injury and certain numbers
野外烤肉.哦,我应该去吗?好的
Barbecue. Oh,did l? See,there you go.
-你在干什么? -太好了,谢谢
-What are you doing? -All right,great.
太棒了,非常感谢,我要去上踢踏舞课
Great. Thanks a lot. I'm going to tap class.
和偷你信用卡的人一起跳踢踏?
To dance with the woman that stole your card?
这样你就可以知道她长什么样子
To see what she looks like.
我可以肯定她的照片就挂在邮局里面
I'm sure her picture's up at the post office.
我应该去看看她是谁
I should get to see who she is.
莫妮卡,你有点失去理智了,你被这件事完全操控
You're kind of losing it here. This is becoming a weird obsession.
我跟你说,这叫做疯狂
This is madness,I tell you.
上帝保佑,莫妮卡别这么做
For the love of God,Monica,don't do it.
谢谢
Thank you.
-你们怎么认为? -很多人
-What do you think? -Lots of things.
-你认为是哪一个? -我能帮你们什么吗?
-Which one is she? -May I help you?
谢谢,我们是来参观的
No,thanks. We're just here to observe.
舞蹈课不是参观的,是来跳舞的
You don't observe a dance class. You dance a dance class.
那儿有舞鞋
Spare shoes are over there.
什么意思?
What does she mean?
我想她是叫我们进去跳
I think she means "You dance a dance class."
-来吧,来吧,来吧 -真的?
-Come on,come on,come on. -Really?
有看见我的分身吗?
Do you see anybody you think could be me?
各位,上回有人在教室留下酸乳空瓶
Last time there were yogurt containers lying around after class.
-希望别再发生那种事 -她可能是你
-Let's not have that happen again. -She could be you.
开始吧
Let's get started.
五,六,五,六,七,八
Five,six. Five,six,seven,eight.
-我跟不上 -我完全融入
-Okay,I'm not getting this. -I'm totally getting it.
你不会觉得,自己有时毫无协调感吗?
Do you ever feel like you're so uncoordinated?
怎么了?只要他们踢的时候你踢就是了
What? You click when they click.
各位找个舞伴
All right,everyone grab a partner.
我死去的妈说就是你,我和瑞秋
All right. And my dead mother said you are it. I'm with Rachel.
这下可好,体育课的旧事又重演了
Great,it's gym class all over again.
无所谓,你过来和我一起跳
You can come up to the front and dance with me.
我何不脱下衣服来场恶梦?
Why don't I just take off my clothes and have a nightmare?
没关系,我来了抱歉,我迟到
It's okay,it's okay. I'm here,I'm here. I'm so sorry I'm late.
来了,那个紧张的新人是谁?
Okay,here I am. So who's the new tense girl?
-你的舞伴 -我叫莫妮卡
-She's your partner. -Hi,I'm Monica.
莫妮卡
Oh,Monica.
我叫莫…
Hi,I'm Mon
-…娜娜 -莫娜娜
-Nana. -Monana.
-是荷兰人的名字 -你在开玩笑吧
-It's Dutch. -You're kidding.
我在阿姆斯特丹住了三年
I spent three years in Amsterdam.
我是德裔宾夕法尼亚州人（语言是夹杂英语的德语）
Pennsylvania Dutch.
开始吧.五,六,七,八
And we're dancing. Five,six,seven,eight.
嗨
Hi.
-你上哪儿去了 -我刚从兽医那回来
-Hey. Where have you been? -I just got back from the vet.
她没叫你戴那种塑胶套吧?
She's not gonna make you wear a big plastic cone?
她说马修乱性不是暂时的
She says Marcel's humping is not a phase.
显然他已性成熟
Apparently,he's reached sexual maturity.
嘿,他超过你呢
Hey,he beat you.
她说他会越来越暴力,侵略性越来越强
She says,as time goes on,he's gonna start getting violent.
这代表什么?
So,what does this mean?
我们不能再养他了
I have to give him up.
我真不敢相信,这真是太扯了
I can't believe it. This sucks.
我不懂,你才刚养他,他怎会突然成熟了?
You just got him. How could he be an adult already?
我知道,之前他只是个小东西
I know. One day he's this little thing...
不知不觉中他就成了紧抓住我的腿不放的小东西
...and then he's this little thing I can't get off my leg.
你没有任何办法再养他吗?
Isn't there any way to keep him?
没办法,兽医说除非有个地方…
No. The vet said unless he's in a place...
…让他获得正常的…
...where he has regular access...
…猴爱
...to some monkey loving...
…否则他会变得愈来愈残暴
... he's just gonna get vicious.
我得将他送到动物园
I just gotta get him into a zoo.
-你如何把他送进动物园? -我知道
-How do you get a monkey into a zoo? -I know.
不,那是教皇进入大众汽车
No,that's popes into a Vokswagen.
我们到处申请,当然大型州立动物园是优先考虑
We're applying to a lot. Our first choice would be a big state zoo.
比方说圣地亚哥动物园
You know,like San Diego. Right?
那可能只是遥不可及的梦想,因为他在加州
But that may just be a pipe dream. He's out-of-state.
兽医说她认识迈阿密的朋友,或许有可能
My vet knows someone at Miami,so that's a possibility.
那儿似乎离海滩只有两条街,一定是个派对动物园
But that's two blocks from the beach. It's a total party zoo.
我们找到她了
We found the girl.
-你们喊警察了吗? -没有,我们和她吃午餐
-Did you call the cops? -We took her to lunch.
你们自己的“自治正义”
Oh,your own brand of vigilante justice.
你疯了?那女人偷了你的东西
Are you insane? This woman stole from you.
她偷东西,她是个小偷
She stole. She's a stealer.
和这女人相处十分钟后,你就会把这些全忘了
After you're with this woman for 10 minutes,you forget that.
她简直是奇女子,振奋人心
I mean,she's this astounding person with this amazing spirit.
她可能是从某位啦啦队队员那儿偷来的
Which she probably stole from some cheerleader.
-脱下他们的帽子 -大众车上的教皇
-Take off their hats. -Popes in a Vokswagen.
我喜欢这个笑话
I love that joke.
-不可能,你不可能这么做 -莫娜娜相当勇敢
-No way. No way did you do this. -Monana was very brave.
我说我们是615房的冈德森姐妹
We told them we were the Gundersons in room 61 5...
结果波士顿塞尔提克已包下整个楼层
...only to find out the Boston Celtics had the entire floor.
他们知道我们又矮又有胸部时
When they saw that we're short and have breasts....
他们就把我们轰出来,我被轰出饭店,我
They threw us out. I was thrown out of a hotel. Me.
干得好,莫娜娜
Go,Monana.
不是只有你们活在梦中
You ladies are not the only ones living the dream.
我得去为我不认识的人倒咖啡,不用等我了
I get to go pour coffee for people I don't know. Don't wait up.
对了
Oh,by the way...
明天我们要去参加百老汇的试演
...tomorrow we're auditioning for a Broadway show.
-什么? -《猫》剧还有一个缺额
-Excuse me? -There's an open call for Cats.
我想我们可以去唱“回忆”
I'm thinking we sing "Memories"...
让自己当个傻子,如何?
...and make complete fools of ourselves. What do you say?
不,记得你身旁的人是谁
No,no,no. Remember who you're dealing with here.
我和你不一样 我连站在踢踏舞教室前都有困难
I can't even stand in front of a tap class.
因为你有门诺教派的血统
That's because of your Amish background.
-什么? -你不是德裔宾夕法尼亚州人吗?
-What? -You're Pennsylvania Dutch,right?
对,直到我买了吹风机被驱逐
（门诺教派后人远离科技产品过着农业生活）
Right. Till I bought a blow dryer. Then I was shunned.
我过去也和你一样 有一天我看了出改变我人生的电影
I was just like you. And then,one day,I saw a movie that changed my life.
看过《死亡诗社》（罗宾・威廉姆斯主演）吗?
Did you ever see Dead Poets Society?
我认为这电影实在是太…无聊了
I thought that movie was so incredibly boring.
那孩子在电影的结局时…
That thing at the end where the kid...
…自杀了.只因他无法演出话剧?
...kills himself because he can't be in the play?
这是在干什么? 他再等一年离家,到社区话剧团去
It's like,"Kid,wait a year. Leave home,do some community theater."
走出电影院时我想,花在这部烂片上的两个小时再也回不来了
I thought,"That's two hours of my life that I'm never getting back."
这想法震惊了我,从此便不再惧怕尝试任何事了
That scared me more than all the other crap I was afraid to do.
那我不敢推荐《窈窕奶爸》（也是罗宾・威廉姆斯主演）了
Wow. Then I would definitely not recommend Mrs. Doubtfire.
上帝
Oh,God.
我们进不了斯克兰顿了
We didn't get into Scranton.
那是我们保底的动物园
That was,like,our safety zoo.
他们连狗和牛都收
They take,like,dogs and cows.
我不懂是我还是他比较难受
See,I don't know who this is harder on,me or him.
我想应该椅子最可怜
I'd say that chair's taking the brunt of it.
马修,马修,马修…不
Marcel. Marcel. Marcel,no.
乖,为何没人要他?
Good boy. See? How can nobody want him?
一定有人会要的
Somebody will.
早就有人叫乔瑟夫斯大林了
You know,there already is a Joseph Stalin.
开什么玩笑
You're kidding.
显然他是屠杀各种民族的俄国独裁者
Apparently,he was this Russian dictator who slaughtered people.
-你怎么会不知道. -你怎么认为我知道
-You'd think you would've known that. -You'd think I would've.
嗨,乔伊・希瑟顿（演员）怎么样
Hey,how about Joey Heatherton?
拜托,我告诉过你不要用回乔伊
Come on,I told you I don't wanna go back to Joey.
菲比 你认为我该取什么艺名?
What do you think a good stage name for me would be?
火焰男孩
Flame Boy.
你的动物园在哪儿?
Where exactly is your zoo?
就技术上而言不算是动物园
Well,it's technically not a zoo,per se.
而是一种互动式野生动物体验
It's more of an interactive wildlife experience.
我想请教你几个关于马修的问题
Let me ask you some questions about Marcel.
-他会和其他动物打架吗? -不会的,他非常温驯
-Does he fight with other animals? -No,no. He's very docile.
如果被逼进角落里去时呢?
Even if he were cornered?
我不知道,干嘛问?
Well,I don't know. Why?
他掌控小东西的能力为何?
How is he at handling small objects?
他会拿香蕉,如果你是这意思的话
He can hold a banana,if that's what you mean.
铁槌或小刀呢?
What about a hammer or a small blade?
为什么?为何要小刀?
Why would he need a blade?
面对有角的动物时
If he's up against an animal with horns...
你得拿些东西给他自我防卫
...you got to give him something.
否则就太残忍了
Otherwise,it's just cruel.
-他能去圣地亚哥了 -什么?
-He got into San Diego. -What?
我们散步回来听见电话铃响
We came back from our walk. The phone was ringing....
然后他就被收下了
He's in.
听见没,马修,是圣地亚哥
Did you hear that,Marcel? San Diego. San Diego.
你大错特错了,圣地亚哥环境良好没错
You're making a mistake. San Diego's good...
如果你把他交给我 我就能训练他对抗瞎眼的兔子
... but I'll start him off against a blind rabbit...
而且我还可以给你百分之二十的门票收入
...and give you 20% of the gate.
你到底跑哪儿去了?
Where have you been?
我和莫妮卡刚跑去参加大使馆舞会
Monica and I just crashed an embassy party.
我想我吻了大主教
I think I kissed an archbishop.
当然,也可能是厨师
But,of course,it could've been a chef.
-你喝醉了? -才没有呢
-Are you drunk? -No.
-骗你的,我醉醺醺的 -天哪
-I'm lying. I am so drunk. -Oh,God.
莫妮卡,你该打电话回来的
You know what? You could've called.
我一直在家里担心你
I've been worried Monica.
好过瘾
Water rules.
没错
Yes. Yes,it does.
餐厅今天又来电话了,他们想知道你还要不要去上班
The restaurant called. They wanna know if you're showing up for work.
不去.我今天要去大苹果马戏团
Nope. Going to the Big Apple Circus today.
你快丢掉工作了,你变了
You're gonna lose your job. This is not you.
不,这正是我
No,it is me.
我不只是那种必须拍松枕头
I'm not just the person who fluffs the pillows...
帐单一来立刻去缴款的人
...and pays the bills right away.
和她在一起,我就超越了那种人
You know,when I'm with her,I'm so much more than that.
我是莫娜娜
I'm Monana.
对,她在,等等
Hello? Yes,she is. Hold on a second please.
莫娜娜,你的电话,信用卡公司打来的
Monana,it's for you. The credit card people.
你好
Hello.
是吗?
Yes?
天呐
Oh,my God.
-谢谢. -怎么啦?
-Thanks. -What?
他们已逮到莫妮卡
They've arrested Monica.
-嗨.-嗨
-Hi. -Hi.
你好吗?
How are you?
不太糟,幸好我喜欢蓝色
Not too bad. Fortunately,blue's my color.
你怎会知道我在这儿?
How did you know I was here?
因为我是莫妮卡盖勒
Because I'm Monica Geller.
你用的是我的信用卡
It was my credit card you were using.
真是没想到
That I was not expecting.
我想让你知道,去报案的人不是我
I want you to know,I didn't turn you in.
-谢谢你 -不,我要谢谢你
-Thanks. -No,thank you.
你带给我太多了
You have given me so much.
如果不是你,我就不可能…
I'd never have gotten to sing...
…在冬园剧场唱“回忆”
... "Memories" at the Winter Garden Theater.
老实说你只开口唱了“回”而已
Actually,you only got to sing "Memo"
我不敢相信你会在这儿 失去你我该怎么办?
I can't believe you're here. What will I do without you?
谁会和我去大使馆宴会
Who's gonna crash parties with me?
谁带我去大苹果马戏团?
Who's gonna take me to the Big Apple Circus?
我在25个女人面前尿尿展开一天的生活
I started my day by peeing in front of 25 other women...
你却担心没人带你去看马戏?
...and you're worried about who'll take you to the circus?
不是担心,只是怀疑
Well,not worried,you know,just wondering.
没什么好怀疑的
There's nothing to wonder about.
你继续做你自己,因为那才是真正的你
You'll go back to being who you were. That's who you are.
-那没必要呀 -那很必要
-Not necessarily. -Yes,necessarily.
我不知道是为什么 或许和你是门诺教派有关
I don't know what it is. Maybe it's the Amish thing.
-我不是门诺教派 -真的?那为何你那么怪?
-I'm not actually Amish. -Really? Then why are you like that?
-门旁边的那个,加不加入? -加入
-You,by the door,in or out? -ln.
-后面的,你完全跳错了 -至少我在跳
-You're getting it all wrong. -But at least I'm doing it.
这是飞往圣地亚哥67次航班的
This is the final boarding call for Flight 67...
最后一次登机通知
... to San Diego at gate 42A.
再见,猴子小伙.这是我给你写的诗
Okay,goodbye,little monkey guy. All right,I wrote you this poem.
上飞机后才能吃
Okay,but don't eat it till you get on the plane.
谢谢你,菲比阿姨
Thank you,Aunt Phoebe.
再见了
Okay,bye,champ.
我知道圣地亚哥那儿,你将有许多宝贝
There'll be a lot of babes in San Diego...
记得要学习的也很多
... but remember,there's also a lot to learn.
我不知该说什么,罗斯,他是一只猴子
I don't know what to say,Ross. It's a monkey.
说出你的感觉就成了
Just say what you feel,Joey.
-马修,我饿了 -这句不错
-Marcel,I'm hungry. -That was good.
马修,这是给你的（好奇乔治）
Marcel,this is for you.
给你,你知道的
It's just,you know,something...
在飞机上玩的
...to do on the plane.
如果不介意我想和他独处一会儿
If you don't mind,I'd like a moment alone.
-当然可以. -继续
-Oh,sure. Absolutely. -Go ahead.
马修,过来,过来,过来
Marcel,come here. Come here. Come here.
小兄弟
Well,buddy...
就这样了
...this is it.
我只想说几句话
Just a couple of things I wanted to say.
我会想你的
I'm really gonna miss you.
我不会忘记你的
You know,I'm never gonna forget about you.
在我心中你不只是一只宠物
You've been more than just a pet to me.
你更是…马修
You've been more like a Okay. Marcel.
能放开我的腿吗?
Would you leave my leg alone?
能暂时不要乱来吗?
Would you stop humping me for two seconds?
马修…带他走好吗?带他走
Okay,would you just take him away? Just take him.
希望我是你手上的手套
Oh,that I were a glove upon that hand...
这样我就能抚摸你的脸颊
...that I might touch thy cheek.
-好了,谢谢. -下一位
-That's fine. Thank you. -Next.
我来试演“马丘修”角色的
I'll be reading for the role of Mercutio.
-名字? -侯登・麦克葛罗尼（谐音holding my groin：握住我那里）
-Name? -Holden McGroin.